KEIN CHAN

chankeinjp@yahoo.co.jp | China:+86 136-7609-1404; Japan:+81 080-9556-9252

ABOUT ME

Senior Full Stack Engineer with over 8 years of experience in server-side development and practical AI/Big-Data projects, aside from server-side development, also has the ability to independently develop iOS and Windows programs.

Provide solutions for the Japanese Government, Toyota, Rakuten Pay, SoftBank, Fuji Film(Xerox), nanamusic, and Fujitsu Network Solutions.

SKILLS & ABILITIES

Programming : Python, Java, Swift, Scala, C#, R

Database: Mysql, PostgreSQL, OracleDB

Data Visualization: PowerBI, Excel
Source Code Version Control: Github, Git

OS: Linux, Windows, MacOS

Cloud Computing: AWS

Virtualized Platforms: Docker, Vagrant

Framework: Spring Boot, Flask, Django, WPF
Test Tools: Pytest, Junit, Selenium, Postman

UI/UX Design: Photoshop, Figma

EDUCATION

2012.04-2014.03 Master Degree, Japan, Osaka University

2010.10-2011.09 Graduated, Japan, Kokusyo Japanese-language school

2004.09-2008.07 Bachelor Degree, China, South China University of Technology

EXPERIENCE

2022.10-Present Full-Stack Engineer, Amigo Technology, Tokyo

Established independent development studio Amigo in Tokyo, working as a full-stack engineer. Engaged in software development services for major Japanese entities like Rakuten Pay, Softbank, and music creation app Nana Music.

- · Led backend team for Rakuten Pay, a prominent electronic payment platform, focusing on credit card and electronic payment/recharge functionality updates.
- Contributed to Softbank's internal project involving Japanese population statistics, utilizing signal base station and GPS location data to manage mobile phone location information for approximately one-third of Japan's population. Responsible for foundational framework verification investigations and some visualization tasks.
- · Additionally, developed a personal project, an iOS app for automatic travel itinerary planning. The app generates travel plans based on user input, including start and end points, mode of transportation, and destination information. It provides information such as map navigation, transit routes, and itinerary schedules.
- Managed backend development and system maintenance for Nana Music, a Japanese music creation app. Addressed real-time system failures caused by version updates and malicious attacks.

2019.09-2022.10 Server-Side Engineer(Section Leader), *Outsourcing Technology, Tokyo*Provided server-side solutions for TRI-AD, Fuji Film(Xerox), and Fujitsu Network Solutions.

- Designed and developed a Microstructure Services System that controls and manages over 3000 robots for Toyota Smart Logistics in Woven City.
- Developed 5 windows applications deploy OCR techs for the census registration system in the Japanese Government.
- Developed a network monitoring system that provides network failure self-detection and visualization for network device management in NTT core network by Fujitsu Network Solutions.

2018.06-2019.08 Test Engineer(QC Manager), Oriental Kingdom Group Co., Ltd, Tokyo

• Responsible for quality control and bug reports of robot control software inside humanoid robot Pepper and central control server system.

2015.10-2018.05 Big Data Engineer, Lamabang Technology Co., Ltd, Shenzhen

- Provided data warehouse infrastructure solutions to cope with the increasing data process needs along with fast user-growth of APP from 300,000 to 3,400,000(DAU).
- Furnish insights, analytics, and business intelligence needed to facility management's decision-making.
- · Monitored and diagnosed for data fluctuation exception.
- Developed an ETL data pipeline using SQL, Shell scripts, Python scripts, scala scripts from various sources that process daily data over 50 TB.
- Designed data warehouse models in accordance with spec requirements for APP statistic report of 3.4 millions DAU.
- Transformed business propositions into quantitative queries and then collected/cleaned necessary data. Created over 200 quantitative reports each year at the request of the Market Operation Department, Advertising Department, and the BI Department.
- Developed an API server to provide data support for server-side development teams.
- Developed an OSS system under database team with over 12 sections of data visualization web pages for routine data analyzing.
- · Introduced machine-learning technology to help business decision-making.

2014.04-2015.09 System Engineer, Lino-a Co., Ltd, Kyoto

• Developed a multi-languages travel information system by WordPress for the inbound traveler.

2008.10-2009.09 Video Editor, Yuanmuyingshi Studio Co., Ltd, Zhuhai

· Responsible for television program and video advertising editing.

CERTIFICATIONS

Java SE8 Gold

Linux Professional Institute Certification LPIC-1

AWS Solution Architect Associate

Python Engineer Certification

Abbyy FC 12 Solution Architect Certification Advanced

IT Passport

Google Analytics Advanced